Van Nhu Nguyen

LOCATION: Södertälje, Sweden PHONE: +46 70 390 07 39

EMAIL: nguyen.van.nhu@vnmedia.se

A experienced developer, a fast learner who passionates about solving complex problem. A team-player and always try to make it easy for people around me. Preferred to spend time with my family or running on my spare time.

KEYWORDS: Kotlin, Python, Golang, NodeJS, C, JavaScript, PHP, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, CouchDB, MongoDB, Spring Boot, Gin, Pyramid, Flask, aiohttp, Celery, ExpressJS, NextJS, ReactJS, React Native, Solr, ElasticSearch, Docker, Nginx, Agile

EXPERIENCE

May 2020 Present

Fullstack developer at Payer Financial Services AB, Stockholm Sweden

Payer is B2B payment service including Card, Swish, Open Banking and Invoicing. My tasks include development and maintaining

- * API platform product
- * Payment integrations and payment widgets
- * Customer onboarding product
- * Backoffices

KEYWORDS

Kotlin, JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJS, ReduxJS, Material UI, NextJS, Jest, Spring Boot, MySQL

August 2017 April 2020

Backend developer at Blocket, Stockholm Sweden

Blocket is number one online classifieds and one of most visited sites in Sweden. Maintain old platform and develop new platform to meet business requirements.

- * API in Python for managing classifieds ads and payment integration
- * Maintain Apache modules, business logic daemon
- * Maintain backoffice

${\sf KEYWORDS}$

Python, C, PHP, PostgreSQL, Nosetests, PHPUnit, Selenium

October 2016 AUGUST 2017

Founder/fullstack developer at Am-lich.com

Event calendar based on Vietnamese (Lunisolar) calendar. A service which you can create own calendars and events and get notification before special days such as Tet (Vietnamese new year).

- * Developing web application, task servers, APIs using Golang
- * Developing web interface using ReactJS
- * Developing Android application using React Native

KEYWORDS

Golang, Gin, FCM, Postfix, PostgreSQL, Redis, Nginx, JavaScript, ReactJS, React Native, Webpack, Android

April 2013 DECEMBER 2016

Backend developer at Tripwell, Stockholm Sweden

Tripwell was a vacation home rental site which made it easy for families and friends to rent privately owned holiday homes in Europe. It was a startup from SCM Ventures.

I have been involved in this project at early stage which mean help finding suitable technology. I had an overview of entire Tripwell platform. I had been there for the team, to support, give advices and recommendations. My daily work involved almost all parts of the code base. The major time I spent doing

- * Payment integration with Trustly/Adyen.
- * Search, building framework for easy setting up and score relevancy of the ads.
- * Integration with partner sites, like blocket.se, tori.fi, finn.no, subito.it, leboncoin.fr
- * API, investigation, design and implementing.
- * Building mock services to mimic external services.
- * Building backoffice for customer support

KEYWORDS

Python, Cython, Pyramid, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Celery, Redis, CouchDB, PostgreSQL, Solr, Nosetests

August 2010 March 2013		
	* Managed and develop new features, maintain business logic daemon and in-house search engine. * Improve and adapt plattform for those new markets, unicode, multilanguage, SEO, Web-performance * PostgreSQL Stored Procedures	
Keywords	PHP, C, Apache module, Nginx, Memcached, Redis, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHPUnit, Selenium	
August 2007 August 2010	•	
Keywords	PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Apache, YUI, Zend framework	

PROJECTS

October 2016	6 Founder/Fullstack developer at Am-lich.com	
Present	Continue develop and maintain the Vietnamese calendar project.	
November 2009	Founder/Fullstack developer at Youtubevideo.isgoodness.com	
FEBRUARY 2011	This project started as hackathon to test Youtube API. The site got a hit on search engine and had its top at 1 million unique visitors per month.	
May 2005	Founder/Fullstack developer at Chinese Poker	
AUGUST 2014	Web-based heads up Facebook game with 10k active users monthly as its best.	
February 2012	Founder/Fullstack developer at Noughts and Crosses	
June 2016	This is a 15x15 multiplayer version using websocket, with bots play against real player.	
July 2011	Founder/Fullstack developer at Igeonote.com	
JULY 2016	For people to share observations, such as I see a rare animal and the position would automatically tagged.	
July 2009	Founder/Fullstack developer at Feedind.com	
AUGUST 2014	Bots collected feeds from blog and news sites and group them in topics. Web application provided search.	
May 2006	Founder/Fullstack developer at VNMedia.se	
MAY 2016	Vietnamese dictionary. It consists also tools and games.	
Keywords	Golang, NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, React Native, PHP, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, CouchDB, Redis, Postfix, Gin, Machinery, CasperJS, Mocha, Vows, Webpack, Websocket, Nginx, Apache	

EDUCATION

Spring 2003	Took some deep-level courses in applied physics, Linköping University.
1997-2002	M.Sc. Applied physics and Electrical engineering, Applied Physics, Linköping University.
1994-1997	Natural science programme, Finnvedens gymnasium, Värnamo.

COURSE & CONFERENCE

2019	Dependency Injection & JPA Systems Operations on AWS PyCon Sweden	2013	PyCon Montreal Schibsted/Blocket Devconf Practical Rhetoric
------	---	------	---

LANGUAGES

SWEDISH	Native or bilingual proficiency
English	Full professional proficiency
VIETNAMESE	Native or bilingual proficiency

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Coding opensource vanng822@github Learning some photography, follow vanng822@instagram Running vanng822@runkeeper